Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have a great lesson for all our upper intermediate students.
今天我们为中高级学生准备了一堂很棒的课。
That's right.
没错。
We're talking about airplane travel today.
我们今天要谈论飞机旅行。
Airplane travel, right.
飞机旅行，对。
So we're going to be in an airplane.
所以我们会在飞机上。
Yes.
是的。
And we're going to be listening to some of the common things you might hear on an announcement
我们会听到一些在飞机广播中常见的说法。
in the airplane.
在飞机上。
Yeah, usually the flight attendant or the captain will come on and say something and
是的，通常空乘或机长会出来说点什么。
well, usually it's in English, so we got to understand what they're saying.
而且通常是用英语，所以我们得听懂他们在说什么。
That's right.
没错。
And we'll also learn some great phrases that you can use when you want to describe flights
我们还会学到一些很棒的短语，当你和朋友聊天时可以用来描述航班。
to your friends when you're talking to them.
当你和他们聊天时。
Yeah, that always happens.
是的，这经常发生。
You arrive somewhere and people are like, hey, how was your flight?
你到了某个地方，人们就会问，嘿，你的航班怎么样？
Now you know how to answer it.
现在你知道怎么回答了。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we take a look at our vocabulary preview?
那我们来看看词汇预览吧？
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, we've got three words for you here in vocabulary preview all about flying.
我们在词汇预览里准备了三个关于飞行的词。
Okay.
好的。
So what's our first one?
第一个是什么？
Turbulence.
湍流。
So turbulence.
所以是湍流。
How can we describe this?
我们怎么描述它？
Well, turbulence when you're in an airplane basically is air that is moving in all directions
嗯，在飞机上，湍流基本上就是空气向各个方向快速移动。
really fast.
快速移动。
Okay.
好的。
So what happens?
那会发生什么？
So the airplane will start to shake.
飞机会开始摇晃。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
It's the same thing if you're flying a kite and maybe some turbulence is in the air, your
就像你放风筝，如果空气中有湍流，你的风筝可能会掉到地上。
kite will maybe fall to the ground.
掉到地上。
Oh.
哦。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's moving in all directions.
所以它是向各个方向移动。
It's really turbulent.
真的很颠簸。
All right.
好的。
Well, we'll hear how this word is used in the dialogue.
我们会在对话中听到这个词怎么用。
But another airplane word we hear a lot.
但另一个我们经常听到的飞机相关词。
Crew.
机组人员。
Flight crew.
飞行机组。
Yes.
是的。
C-R-E-W.
C-R-E-W。
Crew.
机组人员。
So the flight crew is basically the team.
所以飞行机组基本上就是整个团队。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
It's all the people that are in the airplane.
就是飞机上的所有人。
So it's basically the captain and the co-pilot.
所以基本上包括机长和副驾驶。
Yes.
是的。
And all the flight attendants.
还有所有空乘。
Exactly.
正是。
Yeah.
嗯。
So it's basically the flight crew.
所以基本上就是飞行机组。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our last word?
那最后一个词呢？
Bumpy ride.
颠簸的旅程。
A bumpy ride.
Bumpy.
颠簸。
Not smooth.
不平稳。
Yeah.
嗯。
So what would be an example of a bumpy ride?
那颠簸的旅程的例子是什么？
Okay.
好的。
Imagine if you're driving in your car and you're driving on a dirt road, like with many
想象一下你开车在一条土路上，路上有很多坑。
holes in it and everything.
还有各种坑。
And rocks and everything.
还有石头什么的。
Yes.
是的。
You're driving on that road and it would be really, really bumpy.
你开在那条路上，会非常非常颠簸。
Right.
对。
So your car will be moving a lot.
所以你的车会晃动得很厉害。
And shaking.
还会摇晃。
Yeah.
嗯。
So a bumpy ride is a trip where you move and shake a lot.
所以颠簸的旅程就是一趟你晃动得很厉害的行程。
It's kind of uncomfortable.
有点不舒服。
So you can say, that is a bumpy road.
所以你可以说，那是一条颠簸的路。
Or it was a bumpy ride.
或者那是一次颠簸的旅程。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So now let's listen to our dialogue.
那现在我们来听对话吧。
We're going to be listening to these people on an airplane and the captain is going to
我们会听到飞机上这些人，机长会给出一些指示。
give some instructions.
给出一些指示。
And the next thing you know, we're running towards the...
然后接下来，我们就跑向……
Oh.
哦。
Did you feel that?
你感觉到了吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
We're just going through a bit of turbulence.
我们只是遇到了一点湍流。
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain speaking.
女士们先生们，我是机长。
It looks like we've hit a patch of rough air.
看起来我们遇到了一片气流不稳的区域。
So we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes.
所以接下来几分钟会有点颠簸。
This is why I hate flying.
这就是我讨厌坐飞机的原因。
At this time, I'd like to remind all of our passengers to fasten their seatbelts and remain
现在，我想提醒所有乘客系好安全带并保持就座，直到安全带指示灯关闭。
seated until the fasten seatbelt sign is turned off.
直到安全带指示灯关闭。
Please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stowed under the seat in front of you.
请确保所有随身行李妥善存放在您前方座位下方。
I'll be back to update you in a minute.
我一会儿回来更新情况。
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Brent!
Brent！
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
This is totally normal.
这完全正常。
It happens all the...
这经常发……
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain again.
女士们先生们，又是机长。
We've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us.
我们前方还有一大片气流不稳的区域。
And so for your safety, we will be suspending in-flight service.
为了您的安全，我们将暂停机上服务。
I would ask all the in-flight crew to return to their seats at this time.
我请所有机组人员此时回到座位上。
I would also ask that all our passengers refrain from using the lavatory until the seatbelt
我也请所有乘客在安全带指示灯关闭前不要使用洗手间。
sign has been switched off.
在安全带指示灯关闭前。
We can expect...
我们可以预期……
Well, here we are with another dramatic dialogue, another explosion in English.
好了，我们又有了一个戏剧性的对话，又一次英语爆炸。
What's happening?
发生什么了？
I don't know.
我不知道。
A lot of adventure is going on.
很多冒险在发生。
So we'll see what happens.
我们看看会发生什么。
But I'm sure they're all right.
但我相信他们没事。
Don't worry, everyone.
别担心，大家。
I'm sure.
我相信。
Well, I hope so.
嗯，希望如此。
It's kind of making me nervous for my next flight.
这让我对下次飞行有点紧张。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a look at some of the words that the captain used in language takeaway.
那我们来看看机长在语言要点里用的一些词。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
All of these words you'll hear really, really often when you're flying.
这些词你在飞行时经常会听到。
And the first one we have for you is fasten.
第一个是系紧。
Fasten.
系紧。
Fasten your seatbelt.
系好你的安全带。
Now this is a great word.
这是个好词。
Fasten means to...
系紧的意思是……
Do up.
扣上。
Do up or put on or...
扣上或戴上或……
Connect.
连接。
Connect, right?
连接，对吧？
So usually it'll be with a seatbelt or a belt or something like that, right?
所以通常用于安全带或腰带之类的东西，对吧？
Now the pronunciation here is interesting.
这里的发音很有趣。
It's spelt F-A-S-T-E-N.
拼写是F-A-S-T-E-N。
Right.
对。
So it would be fasten.
所以应该是fasten。
No.
不。
No, right?
不对，对吧？
Fasten.
Fasten。
The T kind of becomes silent.
T几乎不发音。
So it's fasten.
所以是fasten。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Let's look at our next word.
我们来看下一个词。
Lavatory.
洗手间。
Okay.
好的。
So what is a lavatory exactly?
那洗手间到底是什么？
Because I'm always confused.
因为我总是搞混。
What's the difference between bathroom, restroom, washroom, WC, lavatory?
bathroom、restroom、washroom、WC、lavatory有什么区别？
I know.
我知道。
So many words for bathroom.
表示厕所的词太多了。
A lavatory is a room with a toilet and sink only.
洗手间是一个只有马桶和洗手池的房间。
Only a toilet and sink.
只有马桶和洗手池。
So no bathtub.
所以没有浴缸。
No.
没有。
No shower either.
也没有淋浴。
No shower.
没有淋浴。
So it's very, very common to find a lavatory in boats, airplanes, or in trains.
所以在船、飞机或火车上很常见。
Yep.
是的。
But never in your house.
但从来不会在你家里。
Never in your house, right?
从来不会在你家里，对吧？
Even if your room in your house is only a sink and a toilet, it's still not a lavatory.
即使你家里的房间只有洗手池和马桶，它也不是lavatory。
It's a bathroom.
它是bathroom。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么。
That's just the way it is in English.
英语就是这样。
And something interesting that you told me today, WC, right?
还有你今天告诉我的一个有趣的东西，WC，对吧？
That's a common thing that you'll see on a bathroom.
这是厕所上常见的一个标志。
Yep.
是的。
What does that stand for?
它代表什么？
Water closet.
水厕。
Yep.
是的。
Wow.
哇。
I didn't know that.
我以前不知道。
Yeah.
是的。
Water closet.
洗手间。
Okay.
好的。
Anyways, let's take a look at our next word.
总之，我们来看看下一个词。
Stow.
放置。
To stow.
Yes.
是的。
Stow your luggage.
放置你的行李。
So if I stow my luggage, it means?
所以如果我把行李放好，这意味着什么？
You put it in a place where you can get it easily, but it is very safe.
你把它放在一个容易拿到但又很安全的地方。
Maybe it's not even visible, right?
可能甚至看不见，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So you put it away in a safe spot.
所以你把它收在一个安全的地方。
Okay.
好的。
So usually in airplanes, they will tell you to stow your luggage under your seat.
通常在飞机上，他们会让你把行李放在座位下面。
Yes.
是的。
Or stow your luggage in the overhead bin.
或者把行李放在头顶行李架上。
Overhead bin or overhead compartment.
头顶行李架或头顶储物箱。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And our last word.
还有我们最后一个词。
Refrain.
克制。
Refrain from doing something.
克制做某事。
So this is a verb, meaning avoid doing.
所以这是一个动词，意思是避免做。
Avoid doing.
避免做。
Do not do.
不要做。
Exactly.
没错。
Something interesting about this grammar-wise is it's usually followed by from.
从语法上来说，有趣的是它通常后面跟着 from。
Yeah.
是的。
Refrain from.
克制。
And the verb that follows is always gerund, right?
而且后面的动词总是动名词，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So refrain from ing.
所以是 refrain from + ing 形式。
Right.
对。
Refrain from using the lavatory.
克制使用洗手间。
Yes.
是的。
Refrain from smoking.
克制吸烟。
Okay.
好的。
So refrain from.
所以是 refrain from。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So some really great examples in language takeaway.
语言摘录中有一些很好的例子。
Yep.
是的。
And well, now let's take a look at Fluency Builder and see some of these great phrases.
好了，现在我们来看看流利度构建器，看看这些好短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right.
好的。
Three phrases we have for you here.
我们为你准备了三个短语。
The first one, remain seated.
第一个，请保持就座。
Remain seated.
请保持就座。
So to remain seated.
所以是保持就座。
Really simple.
非常简单。
To stay sitting.
保持坐着。
To stay on your seat.
待在座位上。
Don't stand up.
不要站起来。
Yes.
是的。
This is really important in airplanes, right?
这在飞机上非常重要，对吧？
Yeah, because otherwise if there's turbulence, you could, you know, end up flying around
是的，因为否则如果有颠簸，你可能会在飞机里飞来飞去。
the airplane.
飞机里。
Or fall, exactly, and hurt yourself.
或者摔倒，没错，伤到自己。
Remain seated.
请保持就座。
Now, one of the reasons they had to remain seated was because they were going to go through
现在，他们必须保持就座的原因之一是因为他们要经过一片气流颠簸区。
a patch of rough air.
一片气流颠簸区。
Patch of rough air.
So patch.
所以是 patch。
Now, interesting.
现在，有趣了。
Okay.
好的。
So patch is a small area, right?
所以 patch 是一个小区域，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So a small area of turbulence.
所以是一小块颠簸区域。
A small area of turbulence.
一小块颠簸区域。
Now, what would be another example of patch?
那么 patch 的另一个例子是什么？
Maybe a patch of strawberries.
可能是一小块草莓地。
So it's like a little strawberry garden, right?
所以就像一个小草莓园，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Or a patch of grass.
或者一小块草地。
Patch of grass.
一小块草地。
Usually in front of your house, you'll have a little patch of grass.
通常在你家门前，你会有一小块草地。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So patch of.
所以是 patch of。
And now our last phrase.
现在是我们最后一个短语。
Suspend.
暂停。
Suspend in flight service.
暂停机上服务。
Yeah.
是的。
So stop for a short time.
所以是暂时停止。
Stop for a short time.
暂时停止。
So you could suspend your work.
所以你可以暂停你的工作。
Yeah.
是的。
And if you're going on vacation, you could suspend your subscription to the newspaper.
如果你去度假，你可以暂停你的报纸订阅。
Okay.
好的。
So suspend to temporarily stop.
所以 suspend 是暂时停止。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So we've covered a lot of vocabulary and some great phrases.
我们涵盖了很多词汇和一些好短语。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue one more time, and we'll come back and talk about
所以我们为什么不听一遍我们的对话，然后回来聊聊飞行。
flying.
飞行。
And the next thing you know, we're running towards the.
然后接下来，我们正跑向……
Oh, did you feel that?
哦，你感觉到了吗？
Yeah, don't worry about it.
是的，别担心。
We're just going through a bit of turbulence.
我们只是遇到了一点颠簸。
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain speaking.
女士们先生们，我是机长。
It looks like we've hit a patch of rough air.
看起来我们遇到了一片气流颠簸区。
So we're going to have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next several minutes.
所以接下来几分钟会有点颠簸。
This is why I hate flying.
这就是我讨厌坐飞机的原因。
At this time, I'd like to remind all our passengers to fasten their seat belts and remain seated
现在，我想提醒所有乘客系好安全带并保持就座，直到安全带指示灯关闭。
until the fasten seat belt sign is turned off.
直到安全带指示灯关闭。
Please ensure that all cabin baggage is carefully stowed under the seat in front of you.
请确保所有随身行李小心地放在你前面的座位下面。
I'll be back to update you in a minute.
我一会儿回来更新情况。
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Oh my God, Brent.
哦，天哪，Brent。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
This is totally normal.
这完全正常。
It happens all the.
这经常发生。
Ladies and gentlemen, this is your captain again.
女士们先生们，又是机长。
We've got quite a large patch of rough air ahead of us, and so for your safety, we will
我们前方有一大片气流颠簸区，为了你的安全，我们将暂停机上服务。
be suspending in-flight service.
暂停机上服务。
I would ask all the in-flight crew to return to their seats at this time.
我请所有机组人员此时回到座位上。
I would also ask that all our passengers refrain from using the lavatory until the seat belt
我还请所有乘客克制使用洗手间，直到安全带指示灯关闭。
sign has been switched off.
直到安全带指示灯关闭。
We can expect.
我们可以预计……
Erica, have you ever had a turbulent flight like this?
Erica，你经历过这样颠簸的飞行吗？
No, no, never this bad.
没有，没有，从来没这么糟过。
A little bit of turbulence.
一点点颠簸。
Actually, I kind of like turbulent flights.
其实，我有点喜欢颠簸的飞行。
Why?
为什么？
It's sort of like, I don't know, it's kind of fun.
有点像，我不知道，有点好玩。
You get shaken around and your stomach moves up and down.
你被晃来晃去，肚子上下起伏。
You don't get nervous?
你不紧张吗？
No, I get a little excited.
不，我有点兴奋。
Well, it is true that flying is actually very, very safe, right?
嗯，确实飞行实际上非常非常安全，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I know we all hear that more people are killed in car accidents than flight accidents.
我知道我们都听说死于车祸的人比死于空难的人多。
So it's very, very safe.
所以非常非常安全。
So yeah, I don't worry about the turbulence.
所以是的，我不担心颠簸。
Knock on wood.
但愿如此。
But yeah, so flying is really safe and you know, as long as you remain seated, you fasten
但是是的，飞行真的很安全，你知道，只要你保持就座，系好安全带，你，你知道，遵守指示，你应该不会有任何问题。
your seat belt and you, you know, you follow the instructions, you shouldn't have any problems.
遵守指示。
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
Actually, that's a really good point because actually when I was reading about flight turbulence
实际上，这说得很好，因为实际上当我为这个对话阅读关于飞行颠簸的资料时，我不断读到这些故事，关于那些人，你知道，当他们遇到一些颠簸气流时，被撞倒或者最终像真的在机舱里飞起来并受重伤。
for this dialogue, I kept reading all these stories about these people who, you know,
真的在机舱里飞起来并受重伤。
when they got into some turbulent air were, you know, knocked over or they ended up like
actually literally flying through the cabin and getting really badly hurt.
真的在机舱里飞起来并受重伤。
So everyone, you got to fasten your seat belt.
所以大家，你必须系好安全带。
Yes, remain seated.
是的，保持就座。
Yeah.
是的。
Flying tips here at EnglishPod.
这里是 EnglishPod 的飞行小贴士。
Flying tips at EnglishPod.
EnglishPod 的飞行小贴士。
We don't want you to get hurt.
我们不想让你受伤。
And we know that you travel a lot, so be safe, right?
我们知道你经常旅行，所以注意安全，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And use this language to describe your flight.
并用这些语言来描述你的飞行。
Okay.
好的。
So come to our website, EnglishPod.com where you can leave questions.
所以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，你可以留下问题。
You can also leave your comments.
你也可以留下你的评论。
Yeah.
是的。
Marco and I are always there.
Marco 和我总是在那里。
And actually, in fact, we have to go check the site now.
实际上，事实上，我们现在得去查看网站了。
So yeah, we're out of time.
所以是的，我们时间到了。
So we'll see you guys next time.
所以我们下次再见。
Thanks for listening.
感谢收听。
Bye.
再见。